

ANUP KUMAR SARKAR

Software Engineer

Work Experience

Ernst & Young Global Limited (EY)

Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2022 - Present

- Responsible for detailed technical design at a solution level. Estimate technical effort, work breakdown structure, risks and solutions for Core Business Service (CBS) Line.
- Responsible for delivery of overall technical solution within schedule and budget. Monitor adherence to methodologies, tools and KPIs.

Healthcare Pharmaceuticals Ltd

Software Engineer, Executive

Dec 2020 - Jan 2022

- By developing a full-fledged Fund & Expense Management System, where external & internal field forces successfully connected with stakeholders. Also helped to automate their task such as fund & expense management, budget controlling, product integration, billings & reporting.
- Newly developed system leads to more than 200% more efficient workflow & effective data tracking & sharing by removing bottlenecks and implementing automations.
- Analyzed & architected business intelligence models to measure ROI, KPI, Risk & Asset management.

The Dhaka Mercantile Co-operative Bank Ltd.

Software Engineer, Assistant Executive

Jan 2018 - Nov 2020

- Developed from scratch a complete ERP software for banking industry focus on key processes such as financial transactions, protecting clients' sensitive info, connecting multiple departments etc.
- Implementing comprehensive Banking ERP software not only provides access to important data, also enabling better Customer Service, Business Process Improvements and **Enhanced Business Reporting**

Education

Bachelor of Computer Applications (BCA) 2014-2017

Lovely Professional University

Puniab. India

CGPA: 7.7 out of 10

Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC) 2009-2011

FM International College Dhaka, Bangladesh **GPA**: 4.70 out of 5.0

Secondary School Certificate (SSC)

Mirpur Siddhanta High School Dhaka, Bangladesh **GPA**: 4.69 out of 5.0

2007-2009

+8801676667712

Github.com/MeAnupSarkar



Leetcode.com/MeAnupSarkar

in Linkedin.com/in/iamanup



Career Summary

Having 4 years of demonstrated experience in designing, architecting and supporting enterpriselevel internet scale services/solutions hosted on Cloud and On-premise technologies. Experience working closely with Software Engineering, especially in the aspects of system performance, capacity management and scalability to ensure sustained service stability & Business KPI's.

Certifications

Microsoft Asp.Net MVC Core with SQL Server

BASIS Institute of Technology & Management (BITM) Duration: 09/2020 - 10/2020



Skills & Expertise

Software Development Life Cycle

Creating vision, Ideation & design thinking, estimates & planning, develop, test, deploy, maintenance, PM & innovation using technologies.

Specialization

Full Stack Web Development Android Application Development

Architectures and Principles

SPA, MVC, SOLID, MVVM, Micro front-ends

Programming languages

C#, JAVA, Typescript, C/C++

Web Technologies

.NET Core/MVC, Entity Framework Core, React,

Redux, ¡Query, Syncfusion, HTML5, CSS3

Data Management

MS SQL Server, MySQL, SQLite, Azure SQL DB, SSIS, SSRS, SSDT

Cloud

Azure (App Services, VM, SQL Database), CI/CD

Machine Learning

Computer Vision using OpenCV & JAVACV

Framework & Library

Android Room, Retrofit, JavaFX, LINQ, DataTable Automapper, Select2, Codelaniter (Php)

Reporting

Crystal Report, RDLC Report

Other

Data Structure & Algorithms, Parallel Processing & Concurrency in C#, Generic, Dependency Injection, Reflections



S WEB APPLICATIONS

1. DMCBL ERP

A complete ERP solution having HRM, CRM, PF, Loan, Banking & Centralized Attendance for The Dhaka Mercantile Co Operative Bank Ltd **Tech Stack:** Asp.net MVC 5, Entity Framework, MS SQL Server 2017, Razor Pages, Bootstrap, jQuery, Crystal Reports, jQuery Datatables

2. Sales & Marketing Activities for Pharmaceuticals Industry

Project containing various sales & marketing automations module creating efficient workflow & effective data tracking & sharing by removing bottlenecks. **Tech Stack:** Dotnet Core 5.0, EF Core, MS SQL Server 2017, Syncfusion, RDLC

Reporting , Bootstrap , jQuery Link: https://ddf.hplbd.com/

3. XEOVENTORY POS & Accounting

Complete solution for POS, Sales, Purchases, Productions, Customers, Suppliers, Transactions, Ledgers, Journal, Receipts & Payments with various reports.

Tech Stack: Asp.net MVC 5, Entity Framework, MS SQL Server

Link: https://xeoventory.azurewebsites.net

4. SapientCerts - Sapient Universal Certifications

Providing real time certificate audit & verifications using QR Code & other technologies.

Tech Stack: ASP.NET Core 5.0 WebAPI, EF Core 5.0, ASP.NET Core Identity,

AJAX for CRUD, Clean Architecture **Link:** http://sapientcert.com/

5. HelloHi Parking

Book/reserve parking spot for your Vehicle anywhere in different cities in US. **Tech Stack:** Php, Codelgniter, MySQL, Bootstrap, Paypal Payment Gateway Link: https://hellohiparking.com/

Open Source Contributions (Desktop Apps)

1. ExoVisix: (AI & Computer Vision)

Auto Attendance System Using Real Time Face Recognition with Various Computer Vision & Machine Learning Tools.

Attendance system Using Face Recognition, Face Trainer, Motion Detection OCR, Gesture Control, Rectangle Shape Detection, Eye Detection.

Tech Stack: Core Java, JavaCV (wrapper of Opency), JavaFX, MySQL, Maven, Tesseract OCR Framework

GitHub Link: https://github.com/MeAnupSarkar/ExoVisix

YouTube Demo: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6UnBZFvY8HE&t=533s

2. XEOCORP Bulk Card Generator:

Generate Bulk/Multiple Business Card by reading files from folder

Tech Stack: Core Java, JavaFx, Google zxing

Link: https://github.com/MeAnupSarkar/Xeocorp-Card-Generator-JavaFX **YouTube Demo:** https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VVIrRC3KttA&t=48s

3. React Redux Typescript Webpack Boilerplate:

Frontend Boilerplate with React, Redux, TypeScript, Webpack, Babel, Ant Design & many more

Link: https://github.com/MeAnupSarkar/ReactReduxTsTemplate

ANDROID APPLICATIONS

1. Vara123

Book or Rent the perfect Accommodation, Parking Spots, Vehicle Rentals in anytime, anywhere in Bandladesh.

Playstore: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.brosoft.vara123

2. BCAS

Android app for content & book sharing for The Institute of Cost and Management Accountants of Bangladesh (ICMAB)

3. HelloHi Parking

Book/reserve parking spot using android app.

Playstore: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.brosoft.hellohiparking

★ Languages

Bengali - Native (Read/Write/Speak)
English - Fluent (Read/Write/Speak)

3. Hindi - Good (Speaking)

Hobbies & Interests

1. Robotics & Al, Blockchain, Automation

2. Cosmology, Science, Travelling, Playing Guitar

3. Reading Books, Novels, Poem History, Ancient Civilizations

4. Sports: Cricket, Chess, Football, Pool

Extra Curriculum

1. Participated Project Expo-2017

Project Developed & Presented: ExoVisix AI

2. Participated Explorica-2016

Project Developed & Presented: StudyPhobia

3. Participated One World Mega Event (India)

Showcasing the culture, heritage & history of BD

Participation Year: 2015, 2016, 2017 Prize/Standings: Runners Up

4. Participated in Hacker Rank World cup

Online coding Competition also various coding competitions in the campus

Personal Information

Father's Name : Kartik Chandra Sarkar

Mother's Name : Anta Rani Sarkar

Permanent Address : Holding#122, Isakabad,

Ward#09, Kaundia, Amin Bazar, Dhaka-1348

Date of Birth : 13th July 1993

Nationality : Bangladeshi

Gender : Male

National ID : 19932694809000112

Marital Status : Unmarried

Declarations

I, the undersigned do hereby state that to the base of my knowledge and belief, the above-mentioned data correctly described my qualification.

(Signature)